Dr. Khalifa: ...Quran that deals with the sad faces and how the sad faces are in the Hereafter.
And he really did fantastic research and he compiled a beautiful list of all the verses in the Quran,
covered the subject completely. Then, when he stood up for the, for the Khutba, this on, for the Prayer,
and he looked at all the most important people on earth in front of him, he forgot everything.
Dr. Khalifa: So, he didn't tell you anything about it. The list was sitting right there, and I saw it, but he was in no condition to be reminded of it.
A man: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: I just want you to know that he did very good research on the subject.
And one of those days, we're gonna have him, we're gonna have him deliver it, when he gets enough courage.
The third item, I would like to apologize for the mess up in the arrangement because of the big crowd, Alhamdu Lillah.
The sleeping section now is divided in two.
John is on this side, and Dan and Francisco are on the other side. So, I don't know, this may cause havoc.
Because it is contagious. So, if I fall asleep, it's because John is on this side.
Dr. Khalifa: Where is Jason? Is he here today? No? I mean, he is missing his mom.
A woman: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: I know, he belongs in the sleeping section. So, I looked, I didn't see him.
Dr. Khalifa: Our teacher tonight is Catherine. And we are in Sura, Catherine: 3
Dr. Khalifa: 3 verse...
Catherine: Page 57.
Dr. Khalifa: Page 57.
Dr. Khalifa: That's very good. A woman: (unintelligible). Catherine: Verse 59.
Dr. Khalifa: Actually, start, yes, ok.
Catherine: At 59? Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: Take it away, Catherine.
Catherine: [3:59] The example of Jesus, as far as GOD is concerned, is the same as that of Adam; He created him from dust, then said to him, "Be," and he was.
[3:60] This is the truth from your Lord; do not harbor any doubt about it.
[3:61] If anyone argues with you after this knowledge has come to you, then say, "Let us summon our children and your children, our women and your women, ourselves and yourselves, then let us invoke GOD's curse upon the liars."
[3:62] This narration is the absolute truth. Absolutely, there is no other god besides GOD. Absolutely, GOD is the Almighty, the Most Wise.
[3:63] If they dispute these facts, then GOD is fully aware of the evildoers.
Someone commented last week that we didn't plan to be talking about Jesus' birth and
the circumstances surrounding that at this time of year. But God planned it that way. And I, for one,
am real grateful that Christmas is over. However, in the process, a lot more people know that
I don't celebrate Christmas. Because I think all of us have had the opportunity to say to people
when they say "Merry Christmas", and "what are your plans for the holidays?" I don't have any special
plans and I'm through with this holiday, why not? It was a good opportunity for all of us who were involved
in that kind of conversation to begin to teach the truth. Not only to the children, as Rashad
talked about, but to the people that are around us who don't know, who've never been exposed
and don't understand. And I think, Lydia, before we started that, one of the things I discovered
in the process was that I do know a lot, but I don't think about it anymore. So much happens on a daily
basis in this mosque. So much information is given to us. I do nothing. I just come here and the sky
opens up and there's more information. And that's true for all of us. It's overwhelming.
And then, we're ready for the next week. We don't even have a chance to process that and there's something
else. So, when someone asks a question who doesn't come here and doesn't know Islam and God alone,
I find that my mind goes blank because I forget a lot of stuff. Because I don't know how to go
back to where they are. And so, this has been a real period of exercise for me to begin to teach people
things that I haven't thought about and that I have taken for granted for a very long time.
These questions that people ask are very basic and they need to be answered by very basic answers,
which I have not thought about. I've just taken for granted as I move through this symphony of information that falls on us.
In verse 61,
[3:61] If anyone argues with you after this knowledge has come to you, ... "Let us summon our children and your children, our women and your women, ourselves and yourselves, then ... invoke GOD's curse upon the liars."
These are the most valuable to us, our families. And
And I'm amazed at how many people insist on bringing this curse upon themselves and their families.
They, they do fight their way to Hell. They insist that their way is correct and they will not hear anything.
Even after they've asked the questions and you've answered them, they, they still won't hear. Their minds
are really closed. It is more than a veil. It is a barrier and it is solid.
And verse 62, again, we have absolutely miraculous proof on a daily basis that what we're reading is God's Voice,
Living Voice to us. All we do is open this book and God is speaking to us. And we have proof of
that, absolute proof, so much proof that we don't even think about that anymore.
We just wait to see how many more numbers there are and how do they fit together. There is absolutely no
way in. There's no way to assail this miracle. There's no way to destroy the code. It is now
so overwhelming. And that's only through Sura 1. We're stuck on Sura 1. I believe that if
all the methods and the research that we've used to date are applied to the rest of the Quran,
I think there's gonna be another torrent and it's gonna be literally years,
even with computers and with everyone working on it, and there are gonna be even more.
How we are gonna teach this to other people, I don't know. We're talking about textbooks because
we've been brought along on a slow basis every day, every week, every month. And to begin to even
explore this with other people, it's, it's overwhelming.
[3:63] If they dispute these facts, then GOD is fully aware of the evildoers.
To you is yours and to me is mine.
[109:2] "I do not worship what you worship. [109:3] "You do not worship what I worship.
I'm not responsible for what you do. And you're not responsible for
what I do. It takes away the need for the argument. And God tells us not to waste
our time with people who do not believe. So, we need to remember that when we're talking with people. Just
leave them. This is what you believe. You've done the best you could. You've delivered the message.
It's up to them. "God willing, you'll have to think about it after you leave."
Catherine: Are there any comments, suggestions, questions up to this point?
A woman: Please go on.
A woman: Yeah, as far as talking to people who think, I find that I don't have to worry about it. I just have to come to my mind when I sit
A woman: and discuss it. It has nothing to do with it. And I don't think there was.
Catherine: Thank God.
Catherine: No one else? I can't see behind me.
Edip: I have a question for you.
Catherine: For me? Edip: Verse 16
Catherine: 16?
Edip: 60
Edip: Verse 60, it says,
[3:60] This is the truth from your Lord; do not harbor any doubts about it.
Edip: First of all, is the messenger addressed by this verse? If the messenger is addressed, how come a messenger...
how a messenger can harbor doubt? (unintelligible) What kind of doubt?
Catherine: One of the messengers has to be reassured and birds
or parts of birds were placed on various hills and falls to reassure that messenger's heart.
I think the human being requires assurance, including the messengers and the prophets.
There are examples all through the Quran of that where God teaches all of the human beings,
including His messengers and prophets. And they do need reassurance.
It's very difficult to take the mantle of prophet and messenger on your shoulders and bear it.
To ask over and over again "Why me? What's required of me?" Moses did that. Abraham. They all did. Lot. Noah.
Catherine: And God supported them and reassured them. So, I think it's a human tendency and God chooses to support the messengers and the prophets more than the rest of us, thank God.
A woman: Did you say that... Dr. Khalifa: Edip, Edip has an answer for...
Edip: No. Dr. Khalifa: No?
A woman: Did you say that the Quran was the Voice of Allah?
Catherine: Yes.
A woman: Well, I don't think that it's (unintelligible) Allah, the Voice of Allah is (unintelligible)
Catherine: ... could hear. I meant that as a metaphor, not as a reality.
A woman: (unintelligible)
Catherine: Edip, did you have something else?
Edip: No, that's okay. But also, I can ask some things...
Edip: I'm confused. To be communicate, to communicate with jinns, with jinns and also to be sick.
These are, this is (unintelligible) these kind of games.
Also, during the time of prophet Muhammad or other messengers,
Edip: some people had this kind of, this kind of Accusation. Dr. Khalifa: Accusation.
Edip: Also, this kind of things. And also, they may because they become suspicious of themselves, they must to be sure that this is
from God. And for this reason, God showed them some miracles, some assurance that
Edip: they are really, they're receiving these revelations from God and make difference between messengers and other people.
Dr. Khalifa: Edip, I want to generalize this. This is for everybody. Edip: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: This verse says,
(3:60) ٱلْحَقُّ مِن رَّبِّكَ
The truth is for...
[3:60] This is the truth from your Lord; have no doubt about it.
[3:61] If anyone argues with you, ... then say,
"Let us call our family."
Dr. Khalifa: So, this is to everybody, including the messengers. Yeah.
Catherine: Verse 64
[3:64] Say, "O followers of the scripture, let us come to a logical agreement between us and you: that we do not worship except GOD; that we never set up any idols beside Him, and never set up each other as gods beside GOD." If they reject such an agreement, then say, "Bear witness that we are Muslims."
[3:65] O followers of the scripture, why do you argue about Abraham, when the Torah and the Gospel were not revealed until after him? Do you not understand?
[3:66] You have argued about things you knew, but why do you argue about things you don't know? GOD knows, while you do not know.
I'm gonna stop here and go back to 64.
A major error that we make, and, and I have to include me in that, is that in casual speech, we attribute
anything and all kinds of things to other people. Even to the driver, as we're driving along, who cuts in front of us too
close. And we say "why did he do that?" Nothing happens that isn't God's doing.
To attribute anything, Rashad uses the, frequently, the example of anything to our boss.
If we get a raise, it came from the boss. If we got chastised, it came from that person. And it has not come from
that person. It has come from God. It's designed for us. And, and it's millions of little ways that
we can remember God every day. My son has just gotten a car recently and has learned to drive,
for example. And there are times when people do some really foolish things on the road. And
he gets very angry, very quickly. And then after that second, he'll turn around and say,
"God did this and I don't need to be angry about it. I need to be a better driver." Alhamdu Lillah,
that will happen. But that's just a minor example that every day in our lives someone will come into
my office, for example, and bring me a book to read. And it will turn out to be something
that I need or have questions about. For example, Edip recently gave a Khutba and was talking about the
decimal places in Pi. And I remember studying that in high school. It so happens that at that
point I got the Reader's Digest at home and there was an incredible article about an Indian man
who memorized 38,000 of those decimal places so far. And he had a favorite section from the 2,000th to
the 3,000th. He liked that section particularly well. So, those kinds of things don't happen
by accident. Everything that happens to us, we need to remember, does not happen as a result of
another person, but as a result of God designing our lives for us to bring us to the truth.
I can't imagine why anyone would want to know that many decimal places in Pi.
And in verse 66, 65 and 66, the reason for argument is many, but it always boils down to ego.
People's ego is affected if they need to argue, especially about things they don't know.
They don't want to appear foolish or they want to obtain something that they don't think is already there, either control of other people
or some status or some power, or to appear different in people's eyes than they really are. So, ego is
almost always involved. And the question about why do we argue about things we don't know is because
we're bad. We're gonna argue about things we don't know. We're going to find a way to justify
what we're doing, even if it's, even if it's saying something we don't know or implying that we know something we don't know.
It's one of the reasons that we need to be extraordinarily careful when we are talking
to that people, to people about the Quran and about God alone. We do really need to know what we're talking about.
And when questions are asked of us that we don't have at our fingertips, we need to research them
and go back with the correct answer and not guess. And again, I speak from personal experience. I
recently have found myself having to say "I don't know. Let me look it up because I don't know." Or
"let me ask." And to get into arguments with people who are, and I've had this experience, too.
Someone who's extraordinarily well-versed in the Bible, the New Testament or the Old Testament,
I'm not. And I don't have the Quran committed to memory. I need to look things up in the Quran,
frequently. So, for me to argue with those people is fruitless. I mean, there's just nowhere for me to go.
So, the point is made that we need to know exactly what we're discussing and not to pretend
Catherine: to know something we don't know. Does anyone have something to add? Or enlarge the Quran in those few verses?
Dr. Khalifa: Yes, I don't think we can pass up 64 without emphasizing this suggestion, this Suggestion from God. It says,
[3:64] Say, "O followers of the scriptures, ...
Jews and Christins
[3:64] ... let us come to a logical agreement ...
that we worship God alone.
So, why shouldn't any Christian or Jew accept this?
What is wrong with this idea of worshiping the One who created us, the One who created the heavens and
the earth, the One who controls our happiness and joy and provisions?
Why, why, why do you think a Christian will not accept this suggestion? "Let us worship God alone and forget the human factors,
Muhammad and Jesus and Mary and so on. The only reason a Christian will reject or a Jew will reject
a suggestion like this would be ego. "How will I face my friends?"
"I'm gonna tell my friends, my relatives, my parents that I don't care about the humans anymore, I only worship God."
"I don't care if Jesus is this or that or if Muhammad is this or that." Therefore, that person is worshiping
his or her ego. It's a logical agreement.
"O, Christians and Jews"
[3:64] ... let us come to a logical agreement between us and you: that we do not worship except GOD; that we never set up any idols besides Him, ...
We come to the realization that idols have no power to benefit you or harm you.
The idols have nothing to do with controlling the rotation of the sun or the moon or the earth,
or the length of day and night, or providing for you. In Sura 29, we read
that the idols you idolize possess no provisions for you. So, seek the provisions from God alone. They can do nothing for us.
So, the agreement is do not worship except God and we never set up any idols beside Him,
and never set up each other as gods beside God. When God tells me that the ablution is 4 steps,
and some other Mulla tells me the ablution is 9 steps, if I do the 9 steps, I'm setting up this Mulla or teacher as a god.
The teachings that you follow come from your god. If you follow the teachings
given to us by God, you're worshiping God. So, this very logical agreement.
And the only reason any Jew or Christian or Hindu or Buddhist would reject it would be ego. And we learn from Quran that
the majority of people in Hell are there because they went along with their relatives or friends.
The Arabic is (29:25) مَّوَدَّةَ بَيْنِكُمْ فِى ٱلْحَيَوٰةِ ٱلدُّنْيَا
Because of your friendship in this life, you sacrifice your Eternal happiness which begins here.
So, you can see the, the logic of it.
We have to be guarding, we have to be very sensitive to the fact that God adorns
the people's beliefs in their eyes. And so, we have to examine our own beliefs. Are we... How do we know we
are not way off and God is adorning our way in our eyes? How do we know? We have to examine ourselves critically.
And you have to examine the logic of your belief, critically. You have to be critical of yourself.
Until you prove that you are not an idol worshipper. You have to start with the assumption
that you are an idol-worshipper, that you're not on the right path. And try very hard to prove
this. If you fail, then you're okay.
So, it's all logic.
65 is telling us that our laws,
our practices, go all the way to Abraham. So, there is no argument between us and the Christians or Jews.
We do not follow the Mosaic laws. We do not follow the Christian's laws, Jesus, the modification that came through Jesus.
We go all the way to Abraham. This is the religion of Abraham, as stated in the Quran.
If we are to pinpoint the prophet through whom God sent scripture to teach us, the practical
scripture came through Abraham, and the Quran came through the prophet Muhammad.
And this lineage, so this verse 65 is telling the Jews and the Christians,
"why are you arguing with us? We have nothing to do with your Mosaic Laws or the Jesus Laws."
And this follows the agreement
in 64, to worship God alone. And as you know, the theme of this book, when you open the front cover,
says, that the Jews, the Christians, the believers, anyone who believes in God and
the Last Day and leads a righteous life, will make it to Heaven. So, we have no argument with
anybody, as long as we all worship God alone. If the Christians or Jews worship God alone,
they worship the same God that I am worshipping. And there, immediately, there is a brotherhood,
right there and then. But once we go down to the human level, human factor, then we fight.
Because my Muhammad will be better than his Jesus, and so on. But as long as we are staying with God
alone, we are united. And the Quran repeats this.
Dr. Khalifa: So, we go back to Catherine and 67, unless there are other additions.
A man: Was Ismail a prophet or...?
Dr. Khalifa: Yes, he was a prophet. Abraham, Ismail, Isaac, and Jacob,
they all got, they all received the practical scripture. We read this in 21:73. God gave, 21:73, yes, God Abraham, Isaac, Jacob,
Ismail the practical scripture.
And this religion continued to be, you know, Abraham's Islam until Moses came.
Dr. Khalifa: 67
Catherine: [3:67] Abraham was neither Jewish, nor Christian; he was a monotheist Muslim. He never was an idol worshiper.
[3:68] The people most worthy of Abraham are those who followed him, and this prophet, and those who believe. GOD is the Lord and Master of the believers.
[3:69] Some followers of the scripture wish to lead you astray, but they only lead themselves astray, without perceiving.
[3:70] O followers of the scripture, why do you reject these revelations of GOD while you bear witness?
[3:71] O followers of the scripture, why do you confound the truth with falsehood, and conceal the truth, knowingly?
[3:72] Some followers of the scripture say, "Believe in what was sent down to the believers in the morning, and reject it in the evening; this may discourage them and may cause them to revert.
[3:73] "You must believe only those who follow your religion." Say, "The right guidance is GOD's guidance." If they claim that they have equally good guidance, or argue with you about your Lord, then say, "All the blessings are in GOD's hand; He bestows them upon whomever He wills." GOD is Bounteous, and Omniscient.
[3:74] He showers His mercy upon whomever He wills; GOD possesses unlimited grace.
67 and 68,
Rashad has already spoken about. Abraham was God's friend. And by bypassing the human factor and
going back to Abraham, we can avoid the pitfalls that majority of people fall into. In 69,
the followers, some people wish to lead you astray. God guaranteed that for those of us who worship
Him alone and work to stay on His path, that we'll be protected from Satan.
In order to do that, however, we need to be knowledgeable about what... we need to have examined ourselves as critically
as Rashad has talked about. Constantly, when someone does ask us questions, that should cause
a critical examination of ourselves and our beliefs and where we got them from.
If we come out of that worshiping God alone and being able to feel secure in what we know, not just believe, but what
we know, we're protected by God. And those people that want to lead us astray will find themselves
quite alone on the Day of Judgment, and certainly without us near them, IN SHAA ALLAH.
In 70,
[3:70] ... why do you reject these revelations of GOD while you bear witness?
We all bore witness before we came to
Earth, and all were given signs through God's Mercy on Earth. God didn't have to do that.
He didn't have to give every single person signs, but He does, and every single day.
Not extraordinary mathematical miracles in each of our lives every day, but in many, many other ways.
The argument with the Jews or the Christians about worshiping God alone, once we're very clear about it,
and when they still refuse by saying "but I do worship God alone." And then I've learned to ask
things like "well, when you pray, do you ever say things like 'we ask this in Jesus' name?'"
"Well, yes, but that's God alone." And it's not God alone, and they can't see the difference. They don't hear the difference.
Again, when people are confounding the truth with falsehood or concealing the truth
knowingly, their ego is, is at work. There's a human tendency to mold God to fit the human needs
as they see them in this life. And so, we ascribe to God what we know as human feelings or human tendencies.
We don't value God as He should be valued, unless we're very fortunate and God guides us to know Him as He really is.
It's interesting to read a lot of anthropological studies when you
listen to music or when you look at art and when you read about primitive peoples and the
gods that they worshipped. They wanted the gods to be like them because that's all they understood.
We still do that, and we know more today. We still do that. There are still people who think that God is
not God, that God does not control everything, that God only can intervene after we have done
everything we can do. And they forget, they don't even get to calling on God because they think they
can do everything themselves. The other thing is fear. People fear letting go of their own ego.
They fear letting go and submitting. The word "submitting" is, is almost adverse to all human beings.
We don't wanna admit that we are submitting to something or someone else. We resent it, as a matter of fact.
Most, most vivid example is, again, something Lydia and I were talking about when we
first came to the mosque. Our feelings, we would get through a whole study and have lots to think
about, and then all of a sudden, everybody got up in line to pray and put their heads down on the floor.
People don't wanna do that. They really don't wanna do that. They look at that and they
go the other way. They find that a very odd thing. They can, they can almost get by the line, they can get by
everybody saying the same words together, and even the bow. But when it comes to prostration, 99% of them
get back out the door as quickly as they can. It's only God's Mercy that I stayed, that Lydia stayed,
that most of us stayed and came and had some more questions. Because Submission and to submit to
someone else or something else is very, very hard for us. We always fight it. That's what we're
taught from the time we're small. And the idea of submitting to God, especially if you don't believe
that God is god, that God is the One from Whom all provisions come, that God is the One that created
this earth and all of us, and that we unwillingly submit whether we want to or not. If you don't
believe that, then, submission is gonna be the same as if you were in prison for the rest of your
life. And people cannot tolerate that thought. So, our ego acts to give us a false sense of
security by refusing to submit to God. And it is a false sense of security. In 72, a common form
of interaction between human beings is deception. And I think we've all been party to this at some level
and not necessarily discussing the worship of God alone. It's easier in some cases to let people
believe that you understand and are in agreement with them. There are many reasons. You might be
after something and the only way to get it is to lead people to believe that you are with them in what they think.
It's a, it's deliberate. We need to understand that deception is a deliberate choice
on the part of a person. You don't deceive someone if you're unaware that you're doing that. You only
deceive if you make a choice to deceive. And if we do that, we're off the path by many miles.
God willing, those of us who are on the path will not be discouraged and will not fall victim to this, but it would be very easy to do.
I think all of us, too, have had opportunities to wonder
as we're talking with people about worshiping God alone and the peace and mercy of that.
People have listened to us, some of them out of politeness, and you can see that they absolutely do not...
They're not... Nothing is falling in. They're just being polite and not hearing.
I think that's a form of deception. I'd much rather have someone say "I don't accept what you're saying."
So, I can say "why?" And we can at least talk about it. But to nod and say "well, yes, and yes" and go away,
that person's gonna see that scene again on the Day of Judgment for sure.
So, there are all kinds of levels of deception. You don't just have to be a... What is the word for a spy in both camps?
Catherine: A double agent. You don't always have to be a double agent. It doesn't have.....
Catherine: We do all kinds of things based on other people's behavior. And if we're around people who are non-believers,
doubts are gonna be able to creep in. We need to stay steadfast and we need to
run as fast as we can when we've delivered the message and there's nothing else to do.
To be with people that also believe. He showers his mercy upon whomever he wills is not a capricious
[3:74] He showers His mercy upon whomever He wills; ...
is not a capricious statement. God isn't up there spinning some dice wondering who's gonna be, He's gonna be Merciful to, today.
That's based on our original decision to worship God or not before we ever came here.
Only God knows who that is. So, it can appear as though people are better off than we by some random
lottery wheel turning. But the fact is that God's Mercy comes to all people, but most especially
to those people who believe. It is not random at all. And God is always there. The more you believe,
the more signs you get. The more you lead a righteous life, the more rewards there are in this
life right now, today. We don't have to wait for them. And God goes beyond that, which is kind of
black and white. And even those people who don't believe, God is Merciful to them. God provides for
them as He provides for us. In some cases, it may appear even more so that those people who are
failing tests right and left and don't even know it. God does not withdraw His mercy on the Day of
Judgment. No one, believer or not, will be able to say they didn't have a million chances every day to remember God alone.
Catherine: Questions? Comments? Please.
Dr. Khalifa: Well, Catherine brought up a very
important point, very important point. That Something that we take for granted. This is the Sujud, prostrations
that we do here in the mosque five times a day, 17 times a day. We prostrate before God. And we have
this message. I want you to listen carefully. We have this message mathematically coded. We know it
is from God. And God is telling us that the people who prostrate before God in this life are the only
ones who will be able to prostrate before God on the Day of Judgment. In Sura 68, we learn from the
Quran that on the Day of Judgment, all creation, angels and jinns and humans, all creation,
will be required to fall prostrate before God. And the people who did not prostrate before God in this
life will not be able to fall prostrate on the Day of Judgment. And they will go to Hell. So, you can, you can
just imagine the importance of this. We take it for granted. We now fall prostrate so easy.
And Catherine mentioned how she and Lydia, in the beginning, which is understandable. It's actually
with all of us, not just two of you. With all of us, it is a difficult thing to bring the highest
place of our body down on the floor. But there is a very important reason behind it. You're
falling prostrate before God. I want you to imagine in your mind now, tomorrow, that tomorrow somebody
is telling you "fall prostrate before God." If you are able to do it, you go
into this fantastic mansion. This is yours. This fantastic mansion with all the pleasures and the
gardens and everything, if we use the allegorical descriptions. If you are able to fall prostrate,
you go into this mansion. If you are unable to, you jump in this fire, so, the big, huge,
pit of fire. And imagine it, put it in practical terms in your mind. Tomorrow, you're required to
do this. If you can fall prostrate before God, you own this great mansion. If you are unable,
you jump in this fire. This is what will happen on the Day of Judgment. And because, I mean,
God puts it straight forward. If you, if you do not make prostration before God here in this world, you
will not be able to do it on the Day of Judgment. You're gonna stand out like a sore thumb,
to use a very mild description.
So, I've been talking the last few days in the morning Quranic
studies and so on, that how the five prayers are a gift from God. If it is only practiced
for that Big Day, which is inevitable for all of us. It is a gift from God to do the five daily prayers.
And I guess, we need this reminder once in a while, so we don't take it for granted. We
take it for granted and it's beautiful. We do it so naturally and so readily. We don't even think
Dr. Khalifa: about it. But it is nice to think about it as a gift from God and thank God for it every chance you get. Douglas.
Douglas: Verses 71 and 72. One of the things that, I think, it says here is that those who
confound the truth with falsehood and distort the scripture, they think that no one knows about it.
We've always... God has already described to us about who has the knowledge. And God is exposing them
in these two verses. They have their own little circle of community and they say,
"yes, we're gonna twist this so the people will believe that." But God is saying at the end of
verse 72, this may discourage them and may cause them to revert. Because
when a person thinks they're doing something in secret and they say "well, no one else knows about this." Then, God reveals,
"I know it. I know what you're doing." In other words, "I'm exposing you in your distortion of
My revelations and scriptures." For some people, it may be a blessing. They may believe this
Douglas: and it may save them. And others, it just may hurt them far worse.
Dr. Khalifa: That's right.
Dr. Khalifa: This reminds me, confounding the truth with falsehood. This is typical of any Christian missionary or preacher
or somebody who comes to your house trying to convert you to Christianity. We were visiting the
great Karmallys, in Vancouver. This is Feroz and Batool Karmally sitting there in the corner.
We were in their house and this Jehovah Witness, very dressed up and everything, he came in to talk
us out of going to Heaven, literally. I mean, he told us that. He said that he had no Heavenly hope
and he wants us to join him. Jehovah Witnesses, they believe that only certain people are going to
Heaven. And he was not one of them and he wants us to join him. But anyway, he came carrying a Bible
and he wanted to teach us the Bible. So, I had him look up John 20:17. Remember this, John 20:17.
You can use it always. John 20:17 says "Jesus says that he's going to my father and your father, my God and your God."
which immediately kills the Trinity. Because this means he's not God
and he's not the only son. "I'm going to my father and your father, my God and your God." So, when I
showed this to this fellow, this Jehovah Witness, his name was Mike, he looked like he never saw it before.
And we ended up telling him at the end "please read the Bible." Here, he came in to tell us
"please read the Bible." And we ended up telling him "please read the Bible." Because he's been... the truth has been confounded for him.
And it's confounded, this is a perfect word because
all their interpretations that lead them to say that Jesus is God or son of God are all roundabout ways.
That word, there is not, a straightforward that says, not one in the whole Bible that says "Jesus is God", for example.
Dr. Khalifa: But it will, it's always derived from "I am the light and" the what? The life
Dr. Khalifa: And... Catherine: The life, the way, the truth, whatever Dr. Khalifa: The way, the truth, the...
Dr. Khalifa: He may be all these, alright, but not God.
But they come out from this saying "Jesus is God."
Dr. Khalifa: Yes, Matt.
Matt: I was reading last night about the Nicene Creed where
the idea of Trinity became dogma. And It turns out that the vast majority of people who were there
to discuss the concept of Trinity didn't approve it. And the people who founded the idea important approved of it.
Matt: And to this day, it's been taught over and over again. A man: It was all politics (unintelligible)
Matt: Huh? A man: Politics.
A man: Ok, what type of politics?
A man: Same true with original sin, right?
Matt: In the Christian doctrine, the idea of original sin wasn't agreed upon until 16th century.
Matt: They couldn't make up their minds whether that was true or not. And finally, when they did make it, it was all around.
A man: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Just to add the time perspective to this, the Nicene Conference was in
325 A.D., 325 years after Jesus. And this is why, when the Trinity was born, 325 years. And Matt
is right in that the majority did not agree. And among the people who did not agree with
the Nicene Creed were the people of the cave, Sura 18. They've been persecuted. They said,
"Our Lord is the Lord of the heavens and the earth. We will not worship anybody else." And that was the
view of the majority of the Christians. But the minority at Nicene that created this Trinity
Dr. Khalifa: business were the people in power. And they forced it by armies and soldiers.
A man: And it was the first Pope that was blind. He was called Blind Pope. He was the first Pope, he got blind.
Dr. Khalifa: They're all blind.
A man: Yeah, I know.
A man: Because he was blind, he got to be blind anyways.
A man: Yes, he can. Dr. Khalifa: I see.
A man: He turned around just five days after that and said "because Jesus was God, we should call Mary, mother of God." And he started that to...
Catherine: Can I just add a funny story about Jehovah's Witnesses? There's a fellow that I've been talking to
about the code in Quran, a person who professes to have some knowledge of the Quran. And we had talked a
long time and finally I said "Look, I'm just gonna give you some stuff to read. You read it and
"come back and talk to me." And what I did was I copied the entire appendix back here and gave it
to him to read. Because he said he had a Quran. And it was some days later, maybe a week later,
he was... he came and he made a joke. He said "Between you and this other person, I'm gonna go nuts with this religion stuff."
I said, you know, "What's the problem?" He said "Well, she's a Jehovah's Witness. And I
"was trying to tell her about the word "God" and how it appears in the Quran, 2,698 times, which
"is a multiple of 19, and about the code. And she told me that the word "God" appears in the Bible,
Catherine: whatever they used, 3 thousand and something." And he said "I got my calculator out and it's a multiple of 19." Dr. Khalifa: Wow!
Catherine: And he went back and told her. So, I know he's reading something, but I thought that was
Catherine: fascinating that One, she would even know that.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes. Catherine: But she hadn't divided anything.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes. Catherine: You know, He went and did that. I thought that was neat.
Dr. Khalifa: Beautiful.
Catherine: I should have listened more closely to the number and where it comes from, but I thought it was pretty funny.
Dr. Khalifa: 75 Catherine: Ok.
[3:75] Some followers of the scripture can be trusted with a whole lot, and they will repay you. And some of them, if you trust them with a single dinar; they will not repay it unless you keep after them. That is because they say, "We do not have to be honest when dealing with the gentiles!"* Thus, they attribute lies to GOD, knowingly.
The footnote says,
*3:75 Prior to the discovery of the Quran's mathematical code, some scholars falsely claimed that Muhammad was an illiterate man who could not write such a great book. They distorted the meaning of the word "Ummy," claiming that it meant "illiterate." This verse proves that "Ummiyyeen" means "gentiles."
And you're gonna have to explain that because I don't know how to. I interpreted
that verse meaning that, that God cautions us all the way through Quran to be honest and truthful in all
of our dealing. And so, I interpreted it on a very concrete level with regard to wills and testifying
Catherine: with loans and contracts of any kind and being fair and righteous with people in general. But I think, there's more here.
Dr. Khalifa: According to the Hadith and Sunnah of the Jews, which is called Talmud,
you can cheat a Gentile, a non-Jew, or steal and even kill. And this is, you're not committing a sin by doing that.
So, the Quran is criticizing this, teaching us to be honest with everybody and anybody because of the
principle that anybody and everybody is a potential believer. So, if you think that
the cashier at the supermarket is a non-believer and he or she gave you $20 by mistake,
you can take it, you're wrong. You're gonna pay dearly for it because of dishonesty. You have to be honest with all the people.
But the point of the footnote is that this verse proves that the word is "Ummy", which
is what the traditional Muslims describe the prophet as, and use it to mean that
he was illiterate, he couldn't read or write. It does not mean a person who does not read or write.
It means Gentile.
Dr. Khalifa: So, it is one of the proofs that the prophet Muhammad wrote the Quran with his own hands. Muhammad.
A man: "Ummiyyeen" (unintelligible), right?
Dr. Khalifa: If you look at Sura 62, God says, He sent to the "Ummiyyeen" a messenger from among them.
So, that was all the tribes of Arabia.
Unless there's a tribe who call themselves "Ummiyyeen"
Dr. Khalifa: that, that I'm not aware of that. But "Ummiyyeen" throughout the Quran means Gentiles. That is people who are not Jews and not Christians.
A man: In Sura that we discussed two weeks ago, (unintelligible) tell to those who received the scripture and (unintelligible). Dr. Khalifa: Yes. Yes.
A man: (unintelligible) a scripture. Dr. Khalifa: Right.
A man: That means...
Dr. Khalifa: is people who did not receive the Torah or the Gospel. Yes, exactly.
It's throughout the Quran, but this is a very straightforward verse, 75, proving that the
prophet Muhammad wrote the Quran with his own hands. For the last 1400 years, they couldn't
figure out what is the miracle of the Quran. Why is it miraculous? Why does God challenge the world
to produce anything like it? And they couldn't come up with anything. So, the best thing they
could come up with was that the prophet Muhammad was an illiterate man, and look at the fantastic
literary work that he produced, or came through him, through him. That's not good enough. Because as a matter
of fact, they were illiterate poets at the time of the prophet, who uttered fantastic poetry,
and they couldn't read and write. So, their argument is down the drain. Fact is,
the prophet Muhammad was able to read and write, among other reasons or proofs is that he was a
merchant. He will take, he was an agent for a number of people. He will take their goods and travel to Syria,
and sell their goods. He had to calculate. You can't be a merchant without calculating a few things.
And it just happens that the numbers in his time were the alphabet. So, he had to know the alphabet
in order to know mathematics and calculation. The evidence is very powerful that he wrote the
Quran with his own hand. This is in addition to the statement in Sura 25, verse 6, where, where his
contemporaries were saying that these are tales from the past that he wrote down and was dictated
to him day and night. So, you don't dictate to an illiterate person. You hire a secretary unless
you're in Washington, Senator, and your secretary is, what's her name?
So you don't dictate to an illiterate person.
There was something else.
Also, in Sura 29, that the proof that the prophet was not illiterate,
Dr. Khalifa: he was able to read and write. He wrote the Quran with his own hand.
A woman: Also, the beginning of Sura 62.
Dr. Khalifa: The beginning of Sura? A woman: 62 Dr. Khalifa: Yes, yes.
Dr. Khalifa: He sent to the "Ummiyyeen."
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A woman: (62:2) يَتْلُوا۟ عَلَيْهِمْ ءَايَـٰتِهِ
A man: Even, even Muhammad's illiteracy cannot be a miracle because it's in favor of (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A man: (unintelligible) He can read. He can spot it. Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A man: (unintelligible)
A man: You have to (unintelligible) the scripture.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A man: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: They are.... it's just a very stupid argument. Their argument is very stupid because even according to their
own stories, it says "the prophet said 'if we capture anybody in war, he can be freed if he teaches somebody how to read and write.'"
Well, he can be the first student if he wanted to, you know. I mean,
If he's urging the people to learn how to read and write, he should have been setting the example,
but the fact is he already knew how to read and write.
So, the evidence is just too overwhelming.
Dr. Khalifa: We have an Appendix 28, I believe, that gives you all the verses and all the evidence. So,...
Dr. Khalifa: There's an important... I'm forgetting, but I'll remember it later on. So, we'll go back to Catherine
Dr. Khalifa: and... Catherine: Verse 76. Dr. Khalifa: 76
Catherine: [3:76] Indeed, if one fulfills his obligations and leads a righteous life, then GOD loves the righteous.
[3:77] As for those who trade away GOD's covenant, and their obligations, for a cheap price, they get no share in the Hereafter. GOD will not speak to them, nor look at them, on the Day of Resurrection, nor will He purify them. They have incurred a painful retribution.
[3:78] Some of them twist their tongues to imitate the scripture, that you may think it is from the scripture, when it is not from the scripture. They, then, claim that it is from GOD, when it is not from GOD. They utter lies and attribute them to GOD, knowingly.
[3:79] Never would a human being whom GOD has blessed with the scripture and prophethood say to the people, "Be worshipers of me besides GOD." Instead, (he would say), "Be devoted to your Lord alone," in accordance with the scripture you received learned.
[3:80] Nor would he command you to set up the angels and the prophets as lords. Would he order you to disbelieve after becoming Muslims?
[3:76] ... if one fulfills ...
Verse 76
[3:76] ... his obligations and leads a righteous life, then GOD loves the righteous.
The "cheap price" in 77 can be a billion dollar lottery
and still be cheap by comparison to the Hereafter. This life is not even one moment compared to
Eternity. It is an illusion. And having that perspective helps us to be ever so much more
peaceful as we go through our lives here. The things that upset other people don't mean
much to us, if anything. Because we know what's going on. We know what's happening. We know why.
We know what our purpose here is, and we know what theirs is. And we're not willing to trade away,
IN SHAA ALLAH, something temporary, some temporary pleasure for all of Eternity.
In the Quran, it says that when God asks "How long have you been here?" of the men and the people in the cave as well,
and they say "One moment, one day, one part of the day." Nothing. We have been here nothing.
I'm reminded of the, of the picture that Rashad drew with dots and saying, you know, compared to Eternity,
do you remember that? It was a long line for Eternity that went on forever and the time
related to us was one dot on the same page that we could barely see. Even if we live to be 150,
it's nothing. There's nothing worth believing in anything other than God alone in this life,
absolutely nothing. I don't care what it is, including what your children do,
what your parents do, what your so-called best friends do. It is not worth getting yourself off
the path of God. It is just not worth it. I would rather live.... rather live, and, and...
But I would be going to school and I wouldn't be working. And I said "I can do this part-time and work, or I can do this full-time
"and we can find a tiny place to live." And he said "take one room, I'll sleep on the floor, you sleep
"on the couch, but get it done." I would rather do that, and all of us would rather do that,
than have the biggest mansions in the world, the most wonderful stable of cars in the world, all
the money in the world. There are so many examples of people who have all those things, but they have
nothing. They have absolutely nothing. None of us would trade away what we have, not one of us
in this room would trade away what we have for anything like that. Mã Shã Allãh.
It is, the "cheap price" is, I don't know how else to make it real to you, it's an illusion. This life is an illusion,
just as the garments that we wear when we greet each other are an illusion. It changes the way we go
through our lives. It changes how we greet each other as human beings in the world. It changes
how we approach other people, whether we know them to be believers or not. It changes everything.
I don't know how many of you saw that incredible rainbow this morning, but that's what our days
are like. All day. Every day. And we don't have mansions. We don't have extraordinary wealth or
power. I wouldn't trade that. I, I, I can't think of anything that's worth that.
Anyway, verse 78,
I think this has been the decade, and we've been watching the news, and all of you have watched TV,
people are trying to sum up the decade of the 80s. And it was interesting the other night because
I watched, and the pictures that flashed were of the evangelist confessing a sin of adultery on TV,
another one saying he would die, like Oral Roberts, he didn't get so many money. I mean,
the flashes were interspersed with many other things, but, evangelists, Muslim scholars, Christians,
the Pope, all of them. They're very convincing. They're very eloquent. And they're very human,
Catherine: and they're very wrong, and they're acting for Satan.
Dr. Khalifa: Oral Roberts said that the Lord told me,
Dr. Khalifa: "if you don't collect $11 million", he will call me. He's got the thing turned around. It should be "If you collect $11 million, I will call you" as a reward.
Catherine: He didn't even get it all.
Dr. Khalifa: It should be something good to go to God, right?
Catherine: Yeah, eventually.
Dr. Khalifa: Quran says that if you're going to Heaven, you should long, you should long for going.
A woman: But they never do.
Dr. Khalifa: But they never do. Catherine: But they never do.
A man: You know what happened? This guy came and gave all the money to him, this lightning struck his TV station, right that moment.
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah. Wow!
A man: (unintelligible)
A man: ...right at that moment. Dr. Khalifa: The man who gave the money.
A man: Right that moment, it was kind of a (unintelligible). And he said "Satan did it. Satan did it." Yeah, he said "Everything, Satan did it."
Catherine: Quran says very frequently "who is more evil than one who attributes lies to God knowingly?" And, I mean,
it's in here many, many, many times, and that's all you hear when you listen to these people.
They really are very clever at using words to distort things. There's enough of the truth buried
in there to attract a great many people, and it's hard to extract it, especially if people are very
facile with their tongues and they have a large vocabulary. However, when some of these things are
so obvious that we laugh here in this mosque, but it's not funny to people out there. These
are people they've listened to every week, every day. They're getting into all kinds of trouble,
and they have to justify what their leaders and scholars are doing. So, while we sit in
here and we kind of laugh at Oral Roberts, and Jimmy Swaggart or I don't even know of...